# Teresa Loaeza Diaz



#### **Coding Apprentice**

Charlotte, NC Tloaezadiaz@gmail.com 980-318-2711

#### LinkedIn

Creative and hardworking software engineer with front-end experience and a desire to develop back-end skills. I take pride in my work quality, my drive to continuously learn new skills and my adaptability which enables success in a fast-paced environment.

### Experience

# Road To Hire(Nov 2021 - present) Coding Apprentice

- Created an e-commerce project using front-end technologies such as HTML and CSS, made it mobile, responsive, and transferred the static project to react.
- Refined my problem-solving skills by completing weekly challenges that focus on advancing front-end technologies.
- Enhanced public speaking skills by presenting four Road Talks throughout the program, maintaining eye contact, vocal variety, and body language while keeping the audience engaged.
- Took advantage of a team-building environment that allowed me to support my classmates by being open to help and giving my feedback when asked.

# Golden Door Scholars(Jun 2021 - Aug 2021)

#### Fellow

- Collaborated with my peers to create an RPG game using Python and present our code and thought process to our instructors.
- Developed an understanding of professional development skills such as time management, networking skills, interview preparation, and financial literacy.
- Exposed to HTML and CSS to create a business website with my peers ensuring equal collaboration.

#### Skills

HTML CSS JavaScript Node.JS React MySQL

## Languages

Spanish- Native

# Volunteer Experience

# Tutor HELPS Organization(Jan 2022 - present)

 Volunteering with the organization HELPS to help elementary school students strengthen their literacy skills to ensure a promising future.

#### **Education**

## Garinger High School(Jun 2021)

- 3.8 GPA
- A/B Honor roll
- A part of Student Government
   Association, pitching ideas for
   school activities, planning school
   events with peers such as spirit
   week, and volunteering after
   school.